ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board photographs 5780/046 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board photographs
1940-1978
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Los Angeles Joint Board
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/046 P
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Photographs.
Consists of photographs transferred from the records of the Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board. Photographs include ILGWU members, officers, and events.
6325230
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 06, 2010
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 14, 2014
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Biographical / Historical
The first local in Los Angeles was founded in March 1907, and due to its low membership, existed for only three months. Approximately three years later (1910-1911), Local 52 was chartered and by 1920 had changed its name to the Cloak, Suit, Skirt, and Reefer Makers' Union of Los Angeles to reflect the broad range of manufacturing within the ladies' garment industry. During the union's struggle with Communism among the membership in the 1920s, the ILGWU General Executive Board (GEB) revoked Local 52's charter in November 1928, alleging Communist corruption and planned secession. The Los Angeles union had to be reorganized, and a new Local 65 was formed with former members who had remained loyal to the ILGWU and the GEB. In 1933, Rose Pesotta was sent to Los Angeles to begin a large scale organization drive. During 1933, both Cutters' Local 84 and Dressmakers' Local 96 were formed. While the strike in October 1933 was ineffective and gains were limited, the strike did prove the successful organizing of Latina dressmakers. At the beginning of 1934, the Los Angeles Joint Board was formed with representatives of Locals 65, 84 and 96. Early board members included H. Rubinstein (manager), L. Pine (chairman), Axelrod (vice chairman), and Paul Berg (secretary). Later that year, Pressers' Local 97 was chartered. As union membership increased, the garment workers began making substantial gains during contract negotiations. Advances were made in wages, hours and holidays. The cloak industry became a closed shop and the sector almost 100% unionized. A new local, 236, was chartered in 1936. During this time, the dressmakers underwent another strike, and Isidore Lutsky was the manager of the Joint Board.
In 1940, the Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board separated from the Dress Joint Board. George Wishnak served as the manager of the Dress Joint Board, and Louis Pine managed the Cloak Joint Board from 1941 until his death in 1946. New production in the sportswear industries necessitated the chartering of Local 266 (sportswear and cotton dress workers). By 1947, Los Angeles became the first in the manufacture of sportswear and second to New York in cloak production. Joseph Springer led the Cloak Joint Board from 1946-1950. The Cloak Joint Board was primarily composed of Operators and Finishers Local 65, Cutters Local 65, and Pressers Local 97. The Dress Joint Board was composed of the large Dressmakers' Local 96 and the cutters and pressers in the dress trade of 84 and 97. These Joint Boards represented much of the skilled workers in the garment industry in Los Angeles, and sights were set on organizing the tens of thousands of unskilled workers. Again, the activities of Communist members within the union began to bring conflict on the west coast, and in 1949, a Special Committee of the ILGWU placed the Cloak Joint Board under the direction of Morris Bagno, and the Dress Joint Board under the supervision of Margaret Di Maggio, to use special powers to remove the remaining Communist influence. In October 1950, Isidore Stenzor took over management of the Cloak Joint Board, a position he would hold until 1970. The ILGWU Health Center for Los Angeles was established in 1951, offering a wide range of service.
The Cloak Joint Board moved to new headquarters in 1955, but the 1950s also saw a shift in production towards sportswear, as membership for Local 266 continued to increase and soon surpass the Operators Local 55 in numbers. In 1955, the ILGWU GEB recommended the merger of the two non-cloak industries, and in September 1955, the Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board was created with manager John Ulene. Ulene retired in January 1968 after 50 years of service with the ILGWU. He had been elected head of the Sportswear Joint Council then managed the combined Dress and Sportswear Joint Board from 1955-1968. Sam Schwartz, the director of organizing for the Joint Board, succeeded Ulene as manager for the Dress and Sportswear Joint Board. With decline in membership and a contraction of the union over the next decades, by December 1970, the Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board and the Cloak Joint Board merged to form the new Los Angeles Joint Board. Stenzor, who had been manger of the Cloak Board since 1950 resigned, and Cornelius Wall, the Western States Region Director, became the manager for the new Joint Board.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the photographic record of the Joint Board of Los Angeles. The images help illustrate the activities of the Joint Board and the locals and include photographs of parades, meetings, and banquets. In terms of membership, there are images of delegates at conventions, officers and managers of the Joint Board, new officers being installed at dinners, board of director luncheons, and group shots of members and factory shots of workers.
There is a large amount of photographs centered around health care, including the City of Hope and Cesar Chavez and the Mobile Health Unit. Of particular interest are the images from the Union Health Center opening in 1951, with photos showing the new facilities, the services offered, and doctors, nurses and patients.
Political images include contract signings, the 1964 and 1972 election campaigns, and rallies against imports in the 1970s. Both David Dubinsky's, and later Louis Stulberg's, visit to Los Angeles are documented. Also, there is much on the union label, including a 1954 union label fashion show, union label clothing from 1960, and Mrs. Brown, wife of then California Governor Pat Brown, sewing in the first union label in California in March 1959.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/046: ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board records 5780/115: ILGWU. Western States Region records
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Women's clothing industry -- California -- Los Angeles; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- California -- Los Angeles; Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- California -- Los Angeles; Industrial relations -- California -- Los Angeles; Antonini, Luigi, 1883-1968.; Balducci, Sally.; Bradley, Thomas.; Brown, Jerry.; Chaiken, Sol.; Chavez, Cesar, 1927-1993.; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982; Feinberg, Basil.; Gluckner, Herta.; Humphrey, Hubert H., 1911-1978.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973; Knight, Goodwin, 1896-1970.; Langer, Hyman.; Otto, Sam.; Rosales, Marie.; Shapiro, Leon.; Stenzor, Isidor.; Stulberg, Louis, 1901-1977.; Ulene, John.; Wanamaker, Maurice.; Union Health Center; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. -- Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board (Los Angeles, (Calif.)).
6325230
- California, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Cloak Joint Board; Labor Day Parade, 1947; ILGWU parade float; LA strikes 1949; Furriers Day 1940.
- California, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  ILGWU Golden Jubilee Convention, Atlantic City, NJ, 1950; Los Angeles 1950.
- California, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Los Angeles 1950- pairs of men passing along documents; City of Hope- Duarte, California, 1950.
- California, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Signing Cloak Contract- Isidor Stenzor, Hyman Langer, Basil Feinberg; Opening of the Union Health Center; Outing of the ILGWU members to the City of Hope; Luncheon attended by Board of Directors of Manufacturers Association and David Dubinsky; NLRB Election, voter lines; David Dubinsky with three patients (Marie Rosales, Herta Gluckner, and Sally Balducci) the City of Hope, standing in front of the ILGWU Hillquit Memorial Hospital at opening; David Dubinsky visits research lab at City of Hope.
- California, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  David Dubinsky visit with patient Joseph Michaels at the City of Hope; David Dubinsky around the City of Hope, multiple images; Luigi Antonini in City of Hope; David Dubinsky at AFL Convention in San Francisco; NLRB Election; Isidor Stenzor at City of Hope, California; Signing contract with Style Trends, October 19, 1951; Allocation Dinner.
- California, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Health care patients in Duarte; Outdoor view, ILGWU Hillquit Memorial Hospital; Speakers at the Allocation Dinner.
- California, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Speakers at Allocation Dinner; ILGWU delegates to AFL State Convention at San Diego; Visit of David Dubinsky and ILGWU Officers to City of Hope; ILG delegates to AFL Convention in San Francisco.
- Union Health Center Los Angeles, Opening., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Reception; Filing; Waiting room; Examination rooms; Pharmacy; Internal medicine; Electrocardiograph; Laboratory; Weighing; Ear, nose, and throat; Eye; Physiotherapy; Radiology.
- Union Health Center Los Angeles, Opening., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Patients receiving services, waiting in line at Union Health Center; CYO children's group at Union Health Center.
- California, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Officers of the Dress Joint Board at the ILGWU 28th Convention; David Dubinsky visits patients at City of Hope; Vice President Otto, Sam and Manager Isidor Stenzor with member of the Association of Contractors; Pacific Region Recovery Board Conference held in Ambassador Hotel in Los Angeles; Cloak Joint Board delegates at California State Convention at the AFL, Santa Barbara.
- California, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Outing of the ILGWU Shop Chairmen, City of Hope; State Convention at the AFL, Santa Barbara; Visiting shops in Los Angeles; Lawn Fair.
- California, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Outing of the ILGWU Shop Chairmen, City of Hope; ILGWU Library; Installation of Cloak Joint Board at City of Hope Chapter; Local 85 Executive Board sponsoring refugee children; Mobile X-ray unit in front of Health Center.
- California, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  General membership meeting, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board, Locals- Embassy Hall; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Installation,; Manager Isidor Stenzor, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; Signing of the new contract between Los Angeles Joint Cloak Board and Coat and Suit Manufacturers Association; Convention, CJB delegation.
- California, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Elections; General membership meeting, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; General membership meeting, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board, Locals- Embassy Hall.
- California, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Cloak Joint Board at Catholic Labor Institute Dinner, Los Angeles; National Conference of Christians and Jews; Pacific Coast Region Delegation, 28th Convention; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Installation; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Elections.
- California, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Los Angeles Sportswear Joint Council Installation Dance; Vice President Sam Otto and John Ulene at Dance; Ratification of Contract of Cloak Joint Board; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Elections.
- California, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Los Angeles Sportswear Council at a convention; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Installation; Dress Joint Board; Los Angeles Sportswear Joint Council Installation Dance; Executive Board of the Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; Combine Executive Board, Joint Board and Dress Sportswear District Council; Election of Executive Committee; Officers of the Dress Sportswear Council.
- California, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Union Label Show, National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board; Governor Goodwin J. Knight and ILG Models at the Union Label Show; Argentine delegation visiting Oscar Strauss Plant; Jogs, Inc., Special refund to workers; Retiree celebration, Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board; Welcome for delegates, Sacramento Typographical Union No. 46 and Women's Auxiliary No. 120.
- California, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Isidor Stenzor and others making a $1,000 contribution to NAACP; Visits to City of Hope; Los Angeles Labor "Ovt" conference; City of Hope Lawn Fair; Delegates of Cloak Joint Board to California State AFL Convention held in Santa Barbara. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff 19
- California, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Los Angeles Labor Ovt, September 1954; Christmas dinner of Jogs shop; Signing of special agreement, Leon Shapiro and Isidor Stenzor; Local 483 Installation; Contract signed with Dumas; Secretary of Labor Mitchell and President David Dubinsky visiting the Deanna Dee shop; Speakers addressing the Cloak Joint Board mass meeting, celebrating the opening of the Los Angeles Coat and Suit Industry Retirement Fund. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff 20
- California, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Cloak Joint Board mass-meeting to celebrate the opening of the Los Angeles Coat and Suit Industry Retirement Fund, held in the Embassy Auditorium; First Cloak retirees; Cloak Joint Board opening of new building; Luigi Antonini and David Dubinsky and other speakers addressing mass-meeting. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff21
- California, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Celebration of the opening of the new Cloak Joint Board building; Ribbon-cutting, speakers, outside view of building (illustration). Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff22
- California, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Celebration Party at Los Angeles Cloak firm; Local 84 Dinner; Celebration of the opening of the new Cloak Joint Board building; California State AFL Convention held in San Diego; Allocations; Recovery Board Conference. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1. ff23
- California, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Assorted shop and dinner scenes; Outside view of Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Building. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff24
- California, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Local 55 election; Officers of Local 512; Executive Board and business agent of Local 97; Election Committee of Locals 58 and 84; Installation of Locals 58, 84, 97, and 512; California State American Federation of Labor Convention in Long Beach; ILGWU Convention in Atlantic City. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1. ff25
- California, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Cutters' Local 84, Executive Board; Voting, Cloak Joint Board. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff26
- California, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Local 55 election, tabulating votes. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff27
- California, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Official signing of the 1957-1960 Cloak agreement; 70th Birthday and retirement banquet, Louis Babitz; Local 84 Banquet; Local 58 Executive Board; Retirement Fund celebration meeting; City of Hope, ILGWU Library; Town Fair. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff 28
- California, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Retirement Fund celebration meeting; Signing of contract; Town Fair outing; Los Angeles Recovery Board Dinner; signing of 1057-1960 Cloak Agreement; Sid Colene Retirement celebration. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff29
- California, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Retirement Fund celebration meeting; Union delegation of Argentine at Local 58 meeting; California State American Federation of Labor Convention in Oakland; Local 58 Executive Board; Sid Colene retirement celebration; Signing of contract with California State Employment Department; James Roosevelt, Congressman, at ILG political rally. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1 ff30
- California, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Women's Campaign rally against "Right-to-Work" amendment; General meeting of the retirees of the coat and suit industry. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff31
- California, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Political Mass Rally; Entertainment at Installation of Officers of Cloakmakers Golden Club; Vice President Samuel Otto, Manager Isidor Stenzor and Local 84 Retirees; Local 512 honoring 512 honoring Carter as Mother of the Year; Women's Campaign rally against "Right-to-Work" amendment. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff32
- California, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Installation of Officers of Cloakmakers Golden Club; Political Mass Rally. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff33
- California, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Installation of Local 55 Executive Board, Los Angeles Cloak Locals; Joint installation. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff34
- California, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Jewish Labor Committee Conference; Installation; Installation of Local 58, 84, 97, 483, 497, 512 Executive Boards. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff35
- California, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  30th Convention, ILGWU, Miami Beach, Florida; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board, ILGWU, Installation of Officers and Executive Board Members; Isidor Stenzor, Manager, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; Union label Show; Argentine delegation at Oscar Straus shop; California Labor Federation Convention, San Diego, California; Jewish Labor Committee Conference. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff36
- California, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Signing of first Los Angeles Cloak designers contract; Contribution to NAACP; Contribution to C.S.O. in Los Angeles; Los Angeles Cloak Golden Club; Japanese delegation; Organization of the Five Wardens. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff1
- California, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Retirees helping in election campaign; Los Angeles Union Label Show; California Federation of Labor Convention, Sacramento, California; Indian labor delegation; Japanese labor delegation. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff2
- California, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Union Label Distribution; "New Horizons" Label Show; mandolin Group; Signing of Los Angeles Cloak Contract; Mailing of political rally; Dumas signing. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff3
- California, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  ILG Educational Director Aileen Hernandez, Fashion Show; Local 58 "Mother of the Year"; Town Fair Booth; Donation to NAACP; Jack Bloom shop. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff4
- California, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  31st Convention, ILGWU, Atlantic City, NJ; Political rally. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff5
- California, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Installation of Cloak Joint Board Officers and Executive Boards. Collection re- boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff6
- California, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  31st Convention, ILGWU, Atlantic City, NJ; Local 97 Executive Board; Golden Age Club; Installation of Locals. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff7
- California, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Severance Paychecks, Baldwin Park shop, Fashion Show workers; Testimonial Dinner for Isidor Stenzor, presentation of trophy. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff8
- California, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Testimonial Dinner for Isidor Stenzor. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff9
- California, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Tot Lines, Inc. Strike; Joint Board Negotiating Committee of Renewal of Contract-; General membership meeting; Local 97 30th Anniversary; President David Dubinsky visiting Los Angeles. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff10
- California, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  J.B. election rally; J.B. Installation; English and citizenship class, Chinatown; Baldwin Park shop, getting severance checks; award given by the California Home for the Aged at Reseda. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, f11
- California, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  J.B. Installation; American Red Cross Award; Local 58 Executive Committee; President Dubinsky and General Secretary-Treasury Stulberg visiting Los Angeles. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, f12
- California, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  National Board of Coat and Suit Industry Conference, Miami Beach; David Dubinsky speaking to crowd of delegates; Isidor Stenzor and Sam Otto, Miami Beach; Farewell, Bon Voyage for Mr. and Mrs. Isidor Stenzor. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff13
- California, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Farewell, Bon Voyage send-off for Mr. and Mrs. Isidor Stenzor. Collection re- boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff14
- California, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Farewell, Bon Voyage send-off for Mr. and Mrs. Isidor Stenzor; Local 55 celebrating the retirement of Maurice Wanamaker; California State AFL-CIO Convention in San Diego; Joint Board and Asian Negotiation Committee for renewal of contract; Workers of Vanguard fashions of California, contributed to Israel Emergency Fund; Shop meeting, Chinatown, San Francisco; Negotiation Committees of the Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; Flu shots with Dr. Igloe; Lou Tabok with Sam Otto; Cutters strike, Geno of California. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff15
- California, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  John Ulene retirement party, Los Angeles; Joint installation of all elected joint board and local officers. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff16
- California, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Joint installation of all elected joint board and local officers; Hubert Humphrey campaign rally; G.E.B. members visiting Los Angeles. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff17
- California, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Joint Campaign meeting, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board and Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board; Thomas Bradley, candidate for Mayor, speaking; Testimonial dinner for Sam Otto on his retirement. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff18
- California, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  John Ulene retirement party, Los Angeles. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff19
- AFL-CIO Convention, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  ILGWU delegates, San Francisco Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff20
- Jerry Brown for Governor Campaign (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff21
- Chavez, Cesar: Presentation of the United Farm Workers Flag, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  March Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff22
- Chic Lingerie Strike (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff23
- Cranston for Controller in Governor Edmund "Pat" Brown Campaign (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff24
- Funny Borex Retirement Party (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff25